akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
Kakashi: Shadow of the Anbu
An Uchiha ANBU
クソッ！
Damn it!
（テンゾウ）相変わらず鮮やかですね。
先輩の雷切。
As usual, your Lightning Blade
is as brilliant as ever, Senpai.
（カカシ）鮮やか？
Brilliant?
暗殺に鮮やかも無様もあるか。
There's no such thing as brilliant
or unsightly in assassination...
殺しは殺しだ。
A kill is a kill, that's all.
（テンゾウ）そういえば
補充はどうなりました？
By the way, what happened
to the replacement?
うちの班の欠員分。
Our team is short a member.
（カカシ）べつに急いじゃいない。
戦時中じゃないからな。
There's no rush.
We're not in the middle
of a war or anything.
そのうち誰か来るさ。
Sooner or later,
someone will show up.
（ガイ）よう　カカシ！
どうした　疲れた顔して。
Hey, Kakashi.
What's up? You look tired.
任務明けか？
（紅）ガイのバカ！
暗部が任務のこと→
Did you just get off a mission?
You're such an idiot, Guy.
外に言うわけないでしょ。
そういうことだ。
Members of the ANBU can't
discuss details of their work!
That's how it goes.
俺たちは　これから
団子屋へ行くんだ。
We're going out for
some sweet dumplings.
お前も　どうだ？
（カカシ）悪い。
- Care to join us?
- Sorry, I don't really like sweets...
甘いものは　ちょっと。
（アスマ）アイツ　すっかり
つきあいが悪くなったな。
He's gotten so antisocial lately.
むぅ。
暗部の秘密主義のせいかしら。
Maybe it's because of
all the secrecy in the ANBU...
いや　そんなことはない！
No! No way!
カカシは俺の永遠のライバル。
心に熱きものがある男だ！
Kakashi is my lifelong rival.
He's got a heart that's filled
with burning passion.
よ～し　こうなったら俺が！
All right, since it's come to this,
it's up to me to do something!
お前が？
You?
暗部に入れてください。
Please let me join the ANBU!
カカシのためにも
それがいちばんです！
It's the best thing to do
for Kakashi's sake!
のう　ガイよ。
Now, now, Guy.
お前が　カカシを心配していることは
よくわかった。
I understand your concern
for Kakashi.
しかし　適材適所というものが
あってのう。
But the saying "the right person
for the right job"
applies to this situation...
暗部では　お前のよさが
発揮できぬだろう。
Your skills will not be optimized
in the ANBU.
いや　俺のことは
いいんです　三代目！
It's not about what's
good for me, Lord Third!
カカシのパートナーとして俺は…。
As Kakashi's partner, I...
うるさい！　お前は
暗部には向かぬのだ！
Silence! You are not suited
for the ANBU.
向く…　向かない…。
Not... suited...
あ…　あの　ダンゾウ様。
（ダンゾウ）何だ？
L-Lord Danzo...
ダンゾウ様のところの
暗部に俺を入れてください！
What is it?
Please accept me
as one of your ANBU!
お前には足りぬな。
You lack it.
は？　何がですか？
Lack what?
闇がだ。
Darkness.
闇？
Darkness?
お前の班に今日から
新人が加わることになった。
A new member will be
joining your team.
例の彼ですか？
Is it the one
we previously discussed?
うむ　実に優秀な忍だ。
Yes, he's extremely capable.
しかし　若いですね。
But he's young.
経験を積ませるべきだと
ダンゾウが推薦した。
Danzo recommended that
he gain more experience.
あなたの装備一式です。
Here's your equipment.
（イタチ）ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
（イタチ）今日から暗部に
所属することになりました→
I've been assigned to
the ANBU from today.
うちはイタチです。
よろしくお願いします。
My name is Itachi Uchiha.
I'd appreciate your guidance.
そうか　キミか。
一番奥のロッカーを使うといい。
I see. So you're the one.
Use the locker that's
the farthest one in the back.
はい。
Yes, sir.
あれか。
１１歳だとよ。
Is that him?
They say he's eleven years old.
暗部最年少じゃねえのか。
Doesn't that make him
the youngest ANBU ever?
ろ班は５分後に
第３演習場に集合だからね。
Team Ro is to assemble at
the Third Training Ground
in five minutes.
はい。
Yes, sir.
（カカシ）何をしている？
What are you doing?
説明しろ。
Explain yourselves!
ここに来るだけの腕があるのか
はっきりさせたくて。
We wanted to make sure he had
the skills to be one of us.
若すぎますからね。
Since he's too young.
上層部の決定に不満か？
Do you have a problem with
the decision of your superiors?
いや　そういうつもりじゃ。
No, it's not like that...
コイツが只者じゃないということは
お前たちも感じているはずだ。
Haven't you already sensed
that he isn't ordinary?
ろ班隊長のカカシだ。
I'm Kakashi, captain of Team Ro.
早急だが　暗部のルール　フォーメーションを
覚えてもらう。
You're new,
but I want you to learn the ANBU
rules and formations quickly.
はい。
Yes, sir.
やるな。
うむ。
He's good.
（テンゾウ）実力は確かですが→
He is talented,
but making an exception
あの歳で暗部に入れるなんて
異例は異例ですね。
for someone so young is
rather unusual for the ANBU.
ダンゾウ様の推薦があったらしい。
Lord Danzo recommended him.
へぇ…
彼　そうは見えませんけどね。
No kidding?
He doesn't fit the mold though.
何がだ？
What do you mean?
ダンゾウ様は　暗部や根の要員に
独自の基準があるようです。
Lord Danzo has
his own personal set of criteria
for ANBU and Foundation agents.
で？
And?
僕からはなんとも。
I just can't see him...
（イタチ）今日から
勤務が始まりました。
I started my duties today.
そうか　さすが俺の子だ。
Is that so? That's my boy.
暗部入り　心から頼もしく思うぞ。
I'm very proud that
you've joined the ANBU.
しかし　これは肝に銘じておけ。
But you must never
forget one thing.
お前は　木ノ葉の暗部である前に
うちは一族のイタチであるとな。
Before you are a Leaf ANBU,
you are first and foremost,
Itachi of the Uchiha Clan.
はい。
Yes, sir.
うちは一族は
木ノ葉の治安を任されているが→
The Uchiha Clan has been entrusted
with the security of
Hidden Leaf Village.
それゆえ逆に
里の中枢から切り離されている。
But because of that,
our clan has been relegated to
living outside
the village boundaries.
一族には
独自の目と耳が必要なのだ。
It is essential that our clan
has one of its own there.
頼むぞ　イタチ。
I am counting on you, Itachi.
（ダンゾウ）うちはフガクは→
Fugaku Uchiha stood out as one of
the shrewdest security captains
歴代の警務隊長の中でも
切れ者の部類だ。
throughout the generations.
さすが
お前の父といったところか。
I'm not surprised that
he's your father.
皮肉ではない。　木ノ葉は
うちは一族に自治権を与えた。
This is not a criticism.
Because the Hidden Leaf
ordered the Uchiha Clan
うちは地区は
里の中枢から切り離されていて→
outside the village limits,
but granted them self-governance,
我らも直接　干渉ができぬ。
we cannot intervene
in their matters.
それゆえに
独自の目と耳が必要なのだ。
Hence, we need our own
set of eyes and ears there.
頼んだぞ　イタチ。
I'm counting on you, Itachi.
（カカシ）少しは慣れたか？
Are you getting used to the job?
（イタチ）まだです。
意外だな。
Not yet.
That's unlike you.
まだ任務に出ていません。
I haven't gone out
on a mission yet.
火影様の護衛も任務のうちだ。
Protecting the Lord Hokage
is a mission in and of itself.
暗部は
暗殺戦術特殊部隊のはずでは？
Isn't the ANBU an assassination
and special tactical unit?
今は休戦中だからな。
Well, we're not at war right now.
カカシよ。
はっ！
- Kakashi...
- Sir?
わしは
あくまで公式に小隊を派遣する。
As the Hokage, every deployment
I order is an official one.
だが　この任務には裏があるという
ダンゾウの意見も無視はできぬ。
However, I cannot
ignore Danzo's view
that there is an underside
to this mission.
そこで
別動隊を非公式に派遣する。
Hence, a separate unofficial team
will be dispatched.
火影からの任務ではない
ということですね。
One that the Hokage didn't order?
ダンゾウからの指示をあおげ。
You will work under Danzo.
（ダンゾウ）表向きは平和外交だ。
On the surface,
this is a diplomatic mission.
林の国の忍　般若衆と
国境で情報の交換を行う。
We will be exchanging intel
with the Hannya Black Ops
of the Land of Woods
at the border.
だが　おそらくこれは
敵の罠であると→
However...
I believe this is an enemy trap.
わしは考えている。
三代目も　これに同意した。
Lord Third agrees with me on this.
通常任務を行う部隊に
暗部が護衛につく。
The ANBU will guard the team
on the official mission.
そして　敵が裏切り
部隊に攻撃を仕掛けてきたら→
When the enemy turns on
the team and attacks, kill them.
殺せ。　１人残らずな。
Leave no survivors.
殲滅ですか？
Total annihilation?
木ノ葉は裏切りを許さぬと
見せつけるのだ。
We must show them
that the Hidden Leaf
does not tolerate betrayal.
イタチとの　ツーマンセルを希望します。
I'd like to be in
a two-man squad with Itachi.
いいだろう。
では。
Fine.
カカシよ
わしは暗部のお前を買っている。
If I may take my leave...
Kakashi...
I recognize your worth
as an ANBU...
改めて
根に引き抜きたいくらいだ。
I'm even tempted to pull you away
into my Foundation.
ご冗談を。
Surely, you jest...
いや　お前には資質がある
闇という資質がな。
I'm serious.
You have the right qualities.
A quality called darkness.
林の国の般若衆と
機密交換を行う。
You will conduct a secret exchange
with the Hannya Black Ops
of the Land of Woods.
木ノ葉からは　この巻物を渡す。
The Hidden Leaf will
hand over this scroll.
般若衆からの巻物と
交換してくるのだ。
And you will accept
a scroll from them.
中身の確認はどうします？
Do we verify the contents?
これは　お互いが
信用できるかどうかの確認だ。
This is a test of mutual trust.
もし　ガセを掴ませられたとしたら→
If they hand over a fake scroll,
それは　林の国が火の国と→
it will prove that
the Land of Woods has no interest
同盟を結ぶ気がない
という証拠だ。
in an alliance
with the Hidden Leaf.
特に何もなければ
そのまま持ち帰ってくるのですね。
So if nothing happens,
we just bring back the scroll?
うむ。　現在　林の国とは
敵対関係にはないが→
Yes. Presently, we have no
hostility with the Land of Woods,
何があるかはわからん。
くれぐれも気をつけてな。
but we cannot be certain.
Be very careful.
お任せください！
Leave it to us!
はっ！
よう　イタチ！
暗部の初任務だな。
Hey, Itachi.
So it's your first ANBU mission.
（イタチ）はい。
カカシ隊長とのツーマンセルだってな。
Right.
I heard it's just Captain Kakashi
and you in a two-man squad.
気をつけろよ。
なんです？
Watch your back.
Why?
隊長は任務のためなら
仲間も殺すからな。
If it's for the sake of a mission,
the Captain won't hesitate
to kill a comrade.
まさに　忍の中の忍だ。
He's a shinobi
of the highest degree.
では　諸君
青春の熱き炎を燃やして　レッツゴー！
Okay, everyone!
Fire up your youthful passion
and... let's go!
（２人）あっ！
待ってください隊長！
Please wait, Captain!
（コスケ）この歳で
青春といわれましてものう。
I'm way past my youthful days...
あの人たちは　この任務の真意を
知らされてはいないのですね。
So they weren't told of
the true nature of this mission?
そうだ。　知っているのは
木ノ葉の上層部と→
No. The only ones who know
are the top ranks of the Leaf
任務を受けた　俺たちだけだ。
and the two of us.
（ガイ）遠出のときに
コスケさんがいてくれるのは→
You're a godsend on
long-distance missions, Kosuke.
実にありがたい。
おかわりもありますので。
Please have seconds.
みんな　しっかり食って
体力も　チャクラも十分に蓄えておけ。
Everyone, eat up and replenish
your energy and chakra.
でも　いいんですか？　隊長。
But Captain, is it wise to burn
a fire out in the open like this?
こんな派手に火をたいて
居場所バレバレですよ。
It's like we're just announcing
that we're here.
もし　敵が襲ってきたら
どうするんですか？
What if the enemy attacks?
襲ってくるというなら
それもいい。
If they want to attack, so be it.
どうやら　俺たちの任務は→
I have a hunch this mission
is to clarify
敵と味方を
はっきりさせることのようだ。
whether they're friend or foe.
意外ですね。
That's amazing.
あの人は任務の表側しか
知らされていないのに→
He's only been told the superficial
facts of the mission,
この任務の本質に気づいている。
but he's figured out
its true purpose.
俺たちも　補給しておこう。
はい。
We should eat too.
Yes, sir.
ある意味　暗部を象徴しているな。
In a way, this symbolizes
the ANBU perfectly.
何がです？
What does?
向こうは　日のあたる場所で
陽気に鍋をつついてる。
They sit out in the sun and
enjoy a hot-pot together.
こちらは　日陰で兵糧丸だ。
While we sit in the shadows
and eat food pills.
大丈夫です　そういう部署だ
ということは→
I don't mind. I realize that
this is part of the job.
わかっていますから。
そうか。
I see.
林の国の般若衆だな。
You're with the Hannya Black Ops
of the Land of Woods, correct?
いかにも　早く巻物をよこせ。
Indeed we are.
Now hand over the scroll!
では　互いに…。
そちらからだ。
- All right then at the same time...
- You first.
いいだろう。
Fine then.
間違いないようだな。
There's no mistake.
そちらの巻物は？
これだ。
And your scroll?
Here it is.
Huh?!
交換するのは巻物だろう。
We're supposed to
exchange scrolls, not fire!
木ノ葉は　約定を違えて
我らに攻撃を仕掛けた。
The Hidden Leaf reneged on
our agreement and attacked us.
よって　これに報復する。
We shall seek retribution.
ずいぶんな言い草だな。
What a bold-faced lie.
約束を破ったのは　キサマらだろう。
You're the one who broke
the agreement!
隊長！
フン。
Captain?!
はなから
裏切るつもりだったのか。
They planned on betraying us
from the beginning!
ここから先は引き受けます。
（カカシ）お前たちは逃げろ。
We'll take over from here.
- You guys get away from here.
- You guys?!
お前ら！
暗部。
増援だ！
- ANBU?!
- Reinforcements!
土遁　岩石崩し！
- Earth Style!
- Rock Collapse!
逃げろ！
Run!
土遁　土流壁！
Earth Style... Mud Wall!
ハハハハハ！
ん？
お前たちは　下がっていろ。
（２人）はい！
Get out of here, you two!
Yes, sir!
噂では　任務のためなら
仲間も殺す人だと。
Rumor has it that
you'd kill a comrade
for the sake of a mission.
俺の仲間は絶対　殺させやしない。
I'll never let
my friends get killed.
それが　この写輪眼と
一緒に託された思いだ。
That's why I was entrusted
with this Sharingan.
お前も逃げろ。
任務の途中で逃げられるか！
You get away from here too.
Like I'd turn my back on a mission!
続けろ！
Get on with it!
土遁　岩石崩し！
- Earth Style!
- Rock Collapse!
八門遁甲　第五杜門　開！
Eight Inner Gates:
Fifth Gate of Closing!
Open!
体術だけで　あれを！
He did that of all that
using only taijutsu?!
感心するのはあとだ！
Save the admiration for later!
うおぉ～！
引け　引け！
Retreat! Retreat!
とりゃ！
あ？
これでお前の任務は終了だ。
Your mission's complete.
里へ戻れ。
ぐわっ！
Return to the village.
おい　何をしてる？
Hey, what are you doing?!
（カカシ）これが
俺たちの受けた任務だ。
This is the mission
we were assigned.
だからって　やめろ　カカシ！
Even still. Stop, Kakashi!
おい　任務中の暗部の名を
呼ぶヤツがあるか！
Hey!
What kind of idiot
calls someone by their name
while they're on an ANBU mission?!
お前…。
あ～っ！
You!
問題ありません　隊長。
Not to worry, Captain.
敵は全滅です。
No enemy survivors remain.
（カカシ）俺は　ダンゾウ様に報告に行く。
I'm going to report back
to Lord Danzo.
お前は任務完了でいい。
Your part of the mission
is complete.
あの…　隊長の写輪眼は→
Captain...
That Sharingan wasn't
originally yours, was it?
自分で開眼したものでは
ありませんよね？
あぁ。
No...
本来の自分とは違う力を
得たことに→
Aren't you uncomfortable
about possessing a power
違和感はないのですか？
that wasn't your own?
あなたは　うちはの者ではない。
You're not an Uchiha.
しかし　写輪眼を持つ以上→
But you possess the Sharingan,
うちはの者と同じ力を使える。
so you wield the same power
as the Uchiha.
自分が　どちらの忍なのか。
Whose side are you on?
そんなふうに考えたことはない。
I've never thought about it
in that way.
この写輪眼は
俺の友から託されたものだ。
A friend entrusted
this Sharingan to me...
俺に　大事なことを
決して忘れるなと。
who made me promise never to
forget what's important.
友から？
あぁ。
A friend?
仲間を殺させるなとな。
To never let a friend get killed.
そうか　ご苦労であったな。
I see, well done.
三代目。
Lord Third...
俺に暗部が向かないというのは
よくわかりました。
I understand why you said that
the ANBU is not suited for me.
そうだろうな。
だからといって→
I see...
But I don't think that Kakashi is
suited to be in the ANBU either.
カカシに暗部が向いているかといえば
俺には　そうは思えません！
そうか。
Is that so?
どうでした？　新人は。
優秀だよ。
How did the newbie do?
He passed with flying colors.
He'll be a better ANBU than me.
俺なんかより　ずっと
優秀な暗部になれる。
いえ
先輩も優秀じゃありませんか。
No, you're an exceptional ANBU,
Senpai...
暗部の任務は
常に闇がつきまとう。
There's a darkness associated
with ANBU missions.
どうしたんです？　今更。
Why are you saying this
all of a sudden?
今更…　そうだな。
All of a sudden? You're right.
味方を騙そうが殺そうが
任務のうちか。
Deception and killing is
all part of the mission...
（サスケ）あっ　兄さん！
Big Brother!
一緒に帰ろう　サスケ。
Let's go home together, Sasuke!
うん！　任務　終わったんだね。
Okay! So you're done
with your mission?
兄さん　聞いて。
Big Brother! Guess what?
今日　俺ね
アカデミーで先生に褒められたんだよ。
My Sensei praised me
at the Academy today.
よう　カカシ。
Hey, Kakashi...
任務のときは　悪かったな。
Sorry about what happened
during the mission.
いや　俺こそ。
No... I'm sorry too.
知っている者もいるだろうが→
Some of you may be aware,
俺の息子のイタチが暗部入りした。
but my son Itachi has
joined the ANBU.
火影や他の上層部のそばで→
Being in close vicinity to
the Hokage and the top ranks
いろいろと知りえることが
増えていくだろう。
means access to more information.
それは　うちは一族にとって
増えていくということだ。
And that is a boon
for the Uchiha Clan.
イタチよ
何か報告することはないか？
Itachi, do you have
anything to report?
はい。
Well...
まだ入隊したばかりで
たいしたことはありませんが→
I'm still new,
so there's not much to report.
今　木ノ葉の上層部は→
However, I don't think
there's solidarity
一枚岩とは言えない状態だと
思われます。
in the higher ranks of the Leaf.
そのなかで　一族は
どう振る舞えばいいのか。
It's my belief that how
the Uchiha Clan deals with this
それが　木ノ葉の未来を
決めることになると思われます。
will determine the future
of the Hidden Leaf.
そうだ　木ノ葉の未来は→
Exactly. By all rights,
本来　うちは一族が
関わるべきことなのだ。
the Uchiha Clan must be involved
in the future of the Hidden Leaf.
（みんな）そうだ　そうだ！
- That's right!
- Right!
- Yeah!
- Yes, that's right!
あれは…。
That's the...
kidzuite ndaro sou sekai ga kataru itsuwari to
I'm sure you've realized by now that the world tells lies
amai wana ni soko ni wa hontou nante nai koto o
And lays alluring traps, but there's no truth behind them
riyuu sagashite run away why? sono mewotojiteru no?
Search for a reason Run away Why?
Why are you closing your eyes?
tell me why can't you
Tell me why can't you
shinjitsu ni te o nobase!
Reach out for the truth!
always (sakebe shout out) all time (tsukame catch up)
Always (Scream, Shout out)
All the time (Catch it, Catch up)
everybody knows (we are the seeker get fire!!!)
Everybody knows (We are the seeker Get fire!!!)
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
tsuyoku aritai to negau nonaraba
if you firmly wish for it
narase narase mezame no kane o
Ring, ring the bell of awakening
koyoi tsuki no shita de kokoro sakebe
Shout from your heart under the moon tonight
utae utae hoero hoero
Sing, sing, howl, howl,
kibou no hikari o nozomu nonaraba
if you want the light of hope
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
akai tsuki no shita de kimi o sakebe
Shout to you under the red moon
ima ima ima flame up (catch the fire)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Catch the fire)
ima ima ima flame up (blaze up!!!)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Blaze up!!!)
Since you've been in the ANBU,
this is a mission that
cannot be avoided.
What kind of mission is this?
Six years ago, during
the incident with the Nine Tails,
The top ranks suspected
that was the Uchiha's doing.
Since then, there's been
round-the-clock surveillance
in the Uchiha district.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
Coup d'État
A mission is a mission.